Professional Summary:

Over 22 years of experience in top multinational ICT sector's companies like **BTC Networks**, **XEROX & Masters Technology**, Directed employees and consultants to maintain a high-level of service by the ICT departments, focused on developing solid solutions in collaboration with all the other actors of the business and its partners.

Seeking a managerial position where I can utilize my managerial, technical skills, experience in Project Management, Telecommunication and ICT to be a part of a multinational professional business environment and working with high calibre personnel.

Area of competences

- Business Development and planning.
- Mega and Rush ICT project management.
- Excellent capabilities on Building strategic relationship with Client and Venders
- Implementation of the ICT strategy, including budgeting.

MANAGEMENT PROFICIENCY

- Drive business growth through aggressive management initiatives that result in increased revenue growth.
- Identify, establish, and manage strategic relationships with clients to leverage significant long term business opportunities.
- Ensure customer service is afforded highest attention and priority.
- Recruit, train and motivate dynamic employees for optimum operations.
- Verify appropriate action plans and performance measurements based on corporate goals and KPI's.
- Team Building Management.
- Project management & Quality assurance.
- Successful build and maintain Client loyalty.
- Strategic thinking, Customer driven and absolute result oriented

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Baud Telecom Company (BTC Networks)

Jeddah, KSA

May. 2013-Present

ICT Project Manager for KING ABDULLAH BIN ABDULAZIZ Third Saudi Expansion of HOLLY HARAM MAKKAH & surrounding area security buildings in SHAMIYA area with Project budget of 330 Million SR (Communication, IT Infrastructure, VoIP, Access Control, light Current and security) within 1st, 2nd and 3rd Fix Scope.

- Manage the Project Delivery includes but not limited to: Achieving the schedule, budget plan, getting customer acceptance, invoicing and collection.
- Participating in PMO to develop project plans of technical packages.
- Report the monthly progress including outlook till year end.
- Preparation Risk Mitigation plan/procedure for project.
- Participating on project progress evaluation reports and progress presentation for stake holders

Masters Technology Company (MTC)

Egypt

2002 to May2013

Chief Information officer

Regional Manager

4 Years

Pre-Sales manager

3 Years

In charge of setting a new mission and vision ensuring that Return on Investment is up to the shareholders expectations.

- Establishing and implementing short / long-range departmental goals, objectives and policies.
- Manage the company Project Delivery includes but not limited to: Achieving the company target plan, getting customer acceptance, invoicing and collection.
- Long Term planning to include a 5 years steady growth.
- Manage the project planning including but not limited to: Complete Market Penetration, Regional Expansion and Customer retention.

- Prepare the company annual business plan including cost budgeting for approval by the BOD timely and
 efficiently.
- Directed and managed project development from beginning to end.
- Supervising the design and cost control of projects.
- Prepare professional business and technical presentations for customers and internal staff.
- Preparing enterprise objectives and budgets to facilitate the orderly and efficient capture, storage, processing, and dissemination of information.
- Reviewing and approving major contracts for computing and information technology services and equipment.
- Emphasize the importance of team work & maintain an atmosphere of mutual respect among the staff.
- Consulted with Engineering/Technical offices to develop appropriate technical solutions.
- Negotiated with vendors and suppliers.
- Purchasing systems where appropriate, Designing, testing, installing and monitoring new systems.
- Being involved in sales and support and, where appropriate, maintaining contact with client organizations.

Projects/milestones:

- Managed projects activities for Broadband/transmission/DSL infrastructure over 330 TE Centrals.
- Managed projects for installing more than 3,000,000 client's ports.
- Managed VoIP projects, communication project/ fiber connectivity projects
- Managed NOC and post sales Customer Service Teams serving more than 250,000 Client.
- Directed and supervised the installation more than 50,000 Customer's ADSL.

Xerox - Egypt Egypt 1992 to 2002

IT Manager 5 Years
Senior IT Infrastructure Engineer 3 Years
Service Engineer 2 Years

- Developing and delivering theoretical and practical training programs to process operatives, ensuring that all the associated functions of preparation, assessment, verification and course development are undertaken
- Field service and support engineer responsible for customer base equipment maintenance
- Provide Technical support to peers
- Identify training and development needs within the organization through job analysis, appraisal schemes
 and regular consultation with business managers.
- Directed computing and IT strategic plans, policies, programs, and schedules for business and finance data processing, computer services, network communications, and management information services to accomplish corporate goals and objectives.

Projects/milestones:

- Project Manager for installing Contract and Billing system and printing network for TE Telecom Egypt within half of Egypt.
- Managed Team for the administration and maintenance of Xerox's infrastructure for both WAN and LAN.

TRAINING COURSES - CERTIFICATES

- Quality: Problem Solving Technique, Customer First., LTQ (Leadership Through Quality), Customer handling and customer's loyalty Guarantee.
- **Technology:** CCNA, CCNP, Local / Wide Area Network (LAN, WAN), Wireless Communications, Microsoft MCP/ MCSE, N+, A+, C++, Network concepts, Field Support, Network Connectivity Management, Designing, Planning and Optimization, System Integration and Migration.
- Other skills: Selling Skills, Team Managements, Training the trainer, Quality Control, Business Process
 Optimization, Contract Negotiation, Customer Service, Forecasting, Vendor Relations, Purchasing and
 Pricina.

Key skills, competencies and personal features

- Excellence mindset striving to exceed expectations. I Advocate teamwork, quality and delegation to build winning profitable companies.
- Strong leadership, team building and motivational skills developed through working on many projectbased tasks. Ability to prospect and analyze different projects needs and accordingly implementing the appropriate action plans needed.
- Self motivated and always accept challenges as they help to explore myself and learn more about my personal capabilities.
- Good negotiation and communication skills. Responsible personality with ability to work hard and under pressure.

Educational Achievements

B. Sc. of Electronic Engineering, Telecomm Dept.
 Menoufeya University, Egypt, 1991

 Microsoft Certified System Engineer MCSE,
 United Nation, OUDA, Egypt 1997

 Project Management Professional
 Global knowledge, Egypt, 2012

Date of Birth: 1 June 1968 Nationality: Egyptian Email: aelmahmoudy@btc.com.sa

Mob #: +966 55 5173922